# Maithri Amarnath Vijayakumari

Sherbrooke, QC | +1 (819) 919-6362 | my3amarnath7@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Process-oriented data analyst with 3 years of experience in optimizing semiconductor manufacturing processes by collecting process data, filtering and identifying patterns from data sets, and generating various types of statistical figures to analyze and turn data into useful insights. I am also an experienced Java Developer in developing PLM applications for 3 years.

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, Java

Libraries/Frameworks: BeautifulSoup, Requests, NLTK, Seaborn, Sci-kit, Keras, TensorFlow, Spark, Hadoop

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Path Finder Tools/Technologies: Advanced JMP, JSL, Power BI, Tableau

Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression, Logistic regression, SVM, K-Means, Random Forest, CNN, RNN, LSTM,

Deep Neural Networks, Ensemble Learning, Clustering.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## INTEL, Leixlip, Ireland

# Process Analyst

October 2020 – November 2023

- Participating as part of an Engineering team to deliver world class performance on critical success indicators (Safety, Quality, Output & Equipment performance) in a highly automated wafer fabrication facility.
- Developing solutions to problems utilizing statistical knowledge and problem-solving tools as well as developing strategies to prevent the recurrence of the problem in future.
- Using data extraction, datamining & analysis skills to identify trends/outliers to reduce process variation & drive corrective action plans.
- Demonstrating Strong analytical & problem-solving skills, team dynamics / ability to work as part of a high performing team.
- Partnering with our 24\*7 technician team to troubleshoot equipment & process issues to facilitate sustaining operations.
- Driving continuous improvement on process & equipment operational indicators to support our future customer demand.
- Demonstrating ability to deal with ambiguity in defining activities and direction, good planning & organization skills, and Excellent communication skills.

# ITC Infotech India Ltd, Bengaluru, India

July 2016 – August 2019

#### **PLM Developer**

- Part of Support and Change Request Development team and interact with clients to understand new business requirements and develop optimized solutions.
- Develop Server Side/Client-Side codes, testing and deployment using Java, JSP and JavaScript on Windows Server environment.
- Interaction with Client Infrastructure team towards Database Server management.
- Worked on APACHE TOMCAT installation, configuration, and load balancer management.
- Extensive experience in development, debugging and testing on Windows.
- Experienced in Software Development Life Cycle models for development and support functions.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

#### MS, Data Science & Analytics

National University of Ireland Maynooth, Ireland

September 2019 – August 2020

## BE, Electronics & Communication Engineering

Visvesvaraya Technological University Bengaluru, India

June 2011 - June 2015

# **ACADEMIC PROJECT**

#### Standardized Water Level Index Reconstruction, Maynooth University

May 2020 – August 2020

Built a predictive model for Standardized water level index using salt-marsh foraminifera as key predictive variable.

- Clustering methods (K-means, Hierarchical clustering) or grouping using PCA were used to explore the impact of minimizing the number of foraminifera spices variables. This helped to understand the relationship between grouped species and tidal elevation.
- A comparison was carried out on prediction model results developed with Random Forest on clustered and non-clustered data.